[
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of Chile?",
        "answer": "Santiago"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where can you find the world`s largest petroglyph?",
        "answer": "Niger -- A life-size drawing of two giraffes known as the Dabous giraffe are located there."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which Southeast Asian city is known as `the city of cats`?",
        "answer": "Kuching, Malaysia -- In Sarawak (Malaysian Borneo)"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the four largest islands of Japan?",
        "answer": "Honshu, Kyushu, Shikoku, Hokkaido"
    },
    {
        "question": "NATO`s headquarters are located in which city?",
        "answer": "Brussels"
    },
    {
        "question": "Lesotho is landlocked by which country?",
        "answer": "South Africa"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many neighbors does Lesotho have?",
        "answer": "Only 1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of Lithuania?",
        "answer": "Vilnius"
    },
    {
        "question": "Red Lake is the largest lake in which US state?",
        "answer": "Minnesota"
    },
    {
        "question": "Libreville is the capital of what country?",
        "answer": "Gabon"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which US state shares a border with the Yukon territory?",
        "answer": "Alaska"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the only venomous British snake?",
        "answer": "Adder"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which US state do the most bald eagles live?",
        "answer": "Alaska"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of the Republic of Nauru?",
        "answer": "Yaren"
    },
    {
        "question": "Yaren is the capital of which country?",
        "answer": "Nauru"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which US President was responsible for the `Louisiana Purchase`?",
        "answer": "Thomas Jefferson"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of Uzbekistan?",
        "answer": "Tashkent"
    },
    {
        "question": "Tashkent is the capital of which country?",
        "answer": "Uzbekistan"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of Niger?",
        "answer": "Niamey"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which US city will you find Louis Armstrong International Airport?",
        "answer": "New Orleans"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Strait of Gibraltar separates Spain and Gibraltar from what African country?",
        "answer": "Morocco"
    },
    {
        "question": "What African country completely surrounds the country of Lesotho?",
        "answer": "South Africa"
    },
    {
        "question": "What famous `Bay` is Jamaica`s fourth largest city?",
        "answer": "Montego Bay"
    },
    {
        "question": "What was the nation of Thailand known as prior to 1949?",
        "answer": "Siam"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Liffey River runs through what European capital city?",
        "answer": "Dublin"
    },
    {
        "question": "What Ivy League university is located in Ithaca, NY?",
        "answer": "Cornell"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of President`s George Washington`s 500 acre Virginia estate, and current tourist attraction?",
        "answer": "Mount Vernon"
    },
    {
        "question": "What US city`s nicknames include `The Crescent City` and `The City that Care Forgot`?",
        "answer": "New Orleans"
    },
    {
        "question": "Albania, Bulgaria, Greece, Bosnia and Herzegovia, Kosovo, and a few other countries make up what peninsula?",
        "answer": "Balkan peninsula"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many US states border Ohio?",
        "answer": "5"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what European country will you find the Spanish Steps?",
        "answer": "Italy"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which country is the Monza Motor Racing Circuit?",
        "answer": "Italy "
    },
    {
        "question": "Into which bay does the Golden Gate Strait lead?",
        "answer": "San Francisco Bay"
    },
    {
        "question": "What event occurs at Walthamstow Stadium?",
        "answer": "Greyhound Racing"
    },
    {
        "question": "What US state includes the telephone area code 505?",
        "answer": "New Mexico"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which city is known as Motown?",
        "answer": "Detroit"
    },
    {
        "question": "Jackson Hole ski resort is located in which US state?",
        "answer": "Wyoming"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Niagara Falls name is derived from an Iroquois word meaning what?",
        "answer": "Thunder"
    },
    {
        "question": "Machu Picchu is located in what country?",
        "answer": "Peru"
    },
    {
        "question": "What site is the home to the famous Intihuatana stone?",
        "answer": "Machu Picchu"
    },
    {
        "question": "Approximately, how many feet above the sea level is Machi Picchu located at?",
        "answer": "8,000"
    },
    {
        "question": "What new Wonder of the World is located in Peru?",
        "answer": "Machu Picchu"
    },
    {
        "question": "What number of latitudinal parallel separates North and South Korea?",
        "answer": "The 38th North"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the deepest lake in the world?",
        "answer": "Lake Baikal"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which countries border Chile?",
        "answer": "Peru, Bolivia and Argentina"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many countries border Chile?",
        "answer": "3"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Arc de Triumphe is to Paris, as the Brandenburg Gate is to what other European capital city?",
        "answer": "Berlin"
    },
    {
        "question": "What two countries edge the Victoria Falls?",
        "answer": "Zimbabwe and Zambia"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what country were Trabant cars made?",
        "answer": "East Germany"
    },
    {
        "question": "Accra is the capital of which country?",
        "answer": "Ghana"
    }
]